# EARL JASON FRANCISCO

Union City, CA 94587 ◆ 510-362-8735 ◆ earljfrancisco@gmail.com

#### Professional Summary

Accomplished IT Support Specialist with over 3 years of information technology support experience with an additional logistics experience and expertise in Desktop Windows/PC and Mac Hardware and Software. Exceptional abilities in troubleshooting and repairing computer related components. Able to work quickly and patiently with end-users in remote and desk-side environments to resolve issues.

## **SKILLS**

- Hardware and Software Installation
- A+ Technician
- Customer Service
- IT Support
- Customer Service
- Troubleshooting Technical Issues

- Computer Repair
- Inventory management
- Mac systems
- Desktop support
- Customer service expert

WORK HISTORY

#### IT Support & Logistics Specialist, 10/2017 to Current

Milestone Technologies @ Facebook - Menlo Park, CA

- Determined hardware and network system issues using effective troubleshooting techniques.
- Created help desk tickets, troubleshot and resolved desktop issues.
- Delivered onsite technical support for 500+ employees.
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- Performed tests of functionality, security and performance of different workstations and devices.
- Provided Tier 1 IT support to non-technical internal users through desk side support services.
- Collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems.
- Loaded software, granted permissions and configured hardware for new employees as part of onboarding process.

## IT Technical Support Representative, 09/2016 to 10/2017

Astreya Partners @ Google - Mountain View, CA

Analyzed issues to identify troubleshooting methods needed for quick remediation

- Collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems
- Submitted service tickets for equipment maintenance requests.
- Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware and network standards and use processes.
- Used internal application ticketing systems to manage and process support actions and requests.
- Documented all transactions and support interactions in system for future reference and addition to knowledge base.

## IT Technical Support, 04/2015 to 08/2016

## Silver Lake Technologies - Palo Alto, CA

- Computer Scans and Anti-Virus (McAfee)/malware removals
- Assist in Installing/Configuring Desktop and Notebook Operating Systems
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data
- Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct hardware problems
- Provide solutions to customers to assist in problem resolution
- Troubleshoot, diagnose and repair for all Dell Portable, Desktop, Workstation & support all Dell-supported OS (Windows 7, Windows 10, Server 2012 r2)

EDUCATION -

Technical Diploma: Computer Information Technology Program, 2018

Unitek College - Fremont - Fremont, CA

- Completed Technical Course
- Majored in Information Technology

**Technical Diploma**: Sterile Processing Technology, 2016

Cornerstone International College - Hayward, CA

• Completed Technical Course